rittal.com 2017-06-10

# Privacy Policy

**Privacy Statement**

Last updated: August 31, 2015

1\. **INTRODUCTION**

Thank you for visiting the www.rittal.us website ("Website"), which is operated by Rittal Corporation ("Rittal" or "we"). This Privacy Policy and Legal Terms of Use (collectively, the “Terms of Use”) govern your use of this Website and applies to Rittal Corporation's collection of information through this Website. 

Our business changes constantly and our Terms of Use will change also. Rittal Corporation reserves the right to change this Terms of Use at any time by posting new Terms of Use on the Website. Please check these Terms of Use from time to time for changes. Your continued use of our Website following the posting of any amendment to these Terms of Use shall indicate your acceptance of the revised Terms of Use.

We collect your personal information because it helps us deliver a superior level of customer service. It enables us to give you convenient access to our products and services and focus on categories of greatest interest to you. In addition, your personal information helps us keep you posted on the latest product announcements and changes, special offers, quality control, warranty information, and events that you might like to hear about.

If you do not want Rittal Corporation to keep you up to date with Rittal Corporation news and the latest information on products and services, you may opt-out by sending an email to [rittal@rittal.us](mailto:rittal@rittal.us) . Please be sure to include your full name, address, phone number and e-mail address, as well as the specific changes you would like to make. This will ensure we correctly identify you in our systems and accurately process your request.

Rittal Corporation will take the appropriate steps to modify your preferences with respect to our marketing communications. Due to production, mailing and system timelines, it may take some time to process your request. Until your requested change takes effect, you may still receive marketing communications from us. 

Although you may have opted not to receive marketing communications, you may still receive business-related communications such as order confirmations, product recall notices, or other related communications.

2\. **TYPES OF INFORMATION COLLECTED**

a. Personal Information 

Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, residential address, personal email address, or personal phone number. Most of the information collected on this Website is business information such as company name, title, company address, business telephone number, and business email address. We do not collect personal information from you unless you supply it voluntary such as when you communicate with us using your personal email address; when you enter a contest or sweepstakes and provide personal information; when you register for a newsletter; or when you provide personal information on the Website. The types of personal information that may be requested include name, date of birth, social security number, personal address, personal telephone number, or other relevant information. 

b. Non-Personal Information 

Our Website captures certain non-personal common technical information automatically. This information may include your Internet protocol (IP) address, browser type and computer operating system, time and date you visit, the pages you access, and the address of the page that directed you to our Website. We use this data to understand patterns of Website activity and to improve the Website so it is more useful for you. This information is not linked in any way to your personal information. 

3\. **PERSONAL INFORMATION DISSEMINATION**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to third parties your personal information unless we provide you with advance notice, except that we may share this data with our subsidiaries and affiliates, as well as the vendors we retain to provide services necessary to our operations. Such third parties could include website hosting companies, public relations companies, advertising and marketing agencies, and mail delivery services companies. The third parties with whom we conduct business are authorized to use your information only to perform the service for which they are hired. They are required to abide by the terms of our Privacy Policy including taking reasonable measures to ensure your personal information is secure. 

We also reserve the right to release personal information in the following circumstances:

  * When we are under a legal compulsion to do so (e.g., we have received a subpoena) or we otherwise believe that the law requires us to do so;

  * When we believe it is necessary to protect and/or enforce the rights, property interests, or safety of Rittal Corporation, our users or others; or

  * As we deem necessary to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, prevent fraud, and otherwise enforce these Terms of Use.

Additionally, in the event that Rittal Corporation is merged with or becomes part of another organization, or in the event that Rittal Corporation is sold or it sells all or substantially all of its assets or is otherwise reorganized, the information you provide will be one of the transferred assets to the acquiring or reorganized entity. We may also transfer personal information to third parties where we are expressly authorized by applicable law to do so.

4\. **COOKIES & OTHER TECHNOLOGIES**

As is standard practice on many corporate web sites, Rittal Corporation‘s Website uses “cookies” and other technologies to help us understand which parts of our web sites are the most popular, where our visitors are going, and how much time they spend there. A cookie is a small text file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service and to better understand how people use our sites. We use cookies and other technologies to study traffic patterns on our web site, to make it even more rewarding as well as to study the effectiveness of our customer communications. And we use cookies to customize your experience and provide greater convenience each time you interact with us. We do this by storing user preferences in cookies and by tracking user trends and patterns of how people navigate our sites. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features or services on our sites may not function properly without cookies. Our cookies do have an expiration date, which is the end of the browser's session.

As is true of most web sites, we may gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

Our Web server automatically collects clickstream information such as the address (or URL) of the web site that you came from before visiting our Website, which pages you visit on our Website, which browser you used to view our site and any search terms you may have entered on our site, among other things. Our Website may also use other technologies to track which pages our visitors view. This anonymous clickstream data provides our customers with a better shopping experience and helps Rittal Corporation understand how visitors use our Website.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Rittal Corporation will not use the information collected to market directly to that person.

In some of our email messages we may use a “click-through URL” linked to content on the Rittal Corporation Website. When customers click one of these URLs, they pass through our web server before arriving at the destination web page. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked simply avoid clicking text or graphic links in the email.

5\. **PERSONAL INFORMATION PROTECTION**

We recognize our responsibility to protect the personal information you entrust to us. We use reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard your personal information in our possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. While we take precautions against possible breaches in our Website and customer databases, no website or Internet transmission is completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized access, hacking, data loss, or other breaches will never occur and cannot be held liable for any unauthorized access or use of the data you have supplied to us. Your use of our Website is at your own risk. We urge you to take steps to protect your personal information when you are on the Internet.

6\. **COLLECTION OF PERSONAL DATA FROM CHILDREN**

Rittal Corporation's web site is not intended for or marketed to persons under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If a child under 13 submits personal information to Rittal Corporation and we learn that that personal information is the information of a child under 13, we will attempt to delete the information as soon as possible. 

7\. **RITTAL CORPORATION’S RIGHT TO CONTACT USERS**

Rittal Corporation reserves the right to contact Website users regarding its privacy policy, or any other policies or agreements relevant to site users.

8\. **LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

The Website may contain links to third party websites not under the control of Rittal Corporation, which may contain information that some people may find offensive or inappropriate. These links are provided solely as a convenience to you and not as an endorsement by Rittal Corporation of the contents on such third-party Websites. Rittal Corporation is not responsible for the content of linked third-party sites and does not make any representations regarding the content or accuracy of materials on such third-party sites. Accordingly, Rittal Corporation is not responsible for the accuracy, copyright compliance, legality, legitimacy or decency of material contained in web sites which may be accessible via a Hyperlink to or from this Website or for the Hyperlink itself. 

If you decide to access linked third-party sites, you do so at you own risk. Rittal Corporation cannot ensure that you will be satisfied with any products or services that you purchase from a third-party site that links to or from the Website, since these sites are owned and operated by independent third-parties. Rittal Corporation does not endorse any of the products/services, nor has Rittal Corporation taken any steps to confirm the accuracy or reliability of any of the information contained in such third-party sites. Rittal Corporation does not make any representations or warranties as to the security of any information you might be requested to give any third party, and you hereby irrevocably waive any claim against Rittal Corporation with respect to such sites. Rittal Corporation strongly encourages you to make whatever investigation you feel necessary or appropriate before proceeding with any online or off-line transaction with any of these third parties.

###  **CONTACT INFORMATION FOR ASKING QUESTIONS AND PROVIDING FEEDBACK REGARDING PRIVACY**

We welcome your questions, comments, and concerns about privacy. Rittal Corporation is committed to the resolution of concerns about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. If you have any questions regarding these Terms of Use or how we protect your personal information, please contact us via email at [rittal@rittal.us ](mailto:rittal@rittal.us) or mail us at:

Rittal Corporation

425 N Martingale Rd

Schaumburg, IL 60173
